(Stop!)
(توقفي!)
(Stop running.)
(توقفي عن الركض)
(Hunt her down.)
(طردوها)
(Stop!)
(توقفي!)
- Stop! - Stop running.
- توقفي! - توقفي عن الركض
- Don't let her get away.
- لا تدعوها تهرب
Hunt her down.
طاردوها
Stop!
توقفي!
Stop! Come on.
توقفي! هيا
(Nie Sangyu)
(نيه سانغ يوي)
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
(Ning Yuxuan)
(نينغ يوي شيوان)
Miss Wen's life is uncertain.
حياة السيدة ون غير مؤكدة
Go back with me.
عودي معي
I didn't kill her!
لم أقتلها!
I told you!
قلت لك!
Ning Yuxuan.
نينغ يوي تشيوان
We've been married for four years.
لقد تزوجنا لمدة أربع سنوات
Why are you pushing me so hard?
لماذا تدفعني بقوة؟
I will say it one last time.
سأقولها مرة أخيرة
Go back.
عودي
Lovebirds got separated.
انفصلت الطيور
The mirror was broken.
تم كسر المرآة
A couple left each other.
ترك الزوجان بعضهما
My husband.
زوجي
I curse you for
ألعنك
a lifetime of despair
بحياة من اليأس
and pain
والألم
like mine,
مثلي
with a tragic end.
بنهاية مأساوية
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
What are you going to do?
ماذا ستفعلين؟
Nie Sangyu!
نيه سانغ يوي!
(My hair just covered my forehead,)
(شعري غطى جبهتي)
(and I folded flowers in front of the door.)
(والحمضيات أمام الباب)
(You came here on horseback,)
(جئت إلى هنا على ظهر الخيول)
(while I was playing with green plum blossoms.)
(بينما كنت ألعب أزهار البرقوق الأخضر)
(When I married you at 14 years old,)
(عندما تزوجتك في سن 14 عاما،)
(I was too shy to smile.)
(كنت خجلة جدا من أن أبتسم)
(I only stretched my eyebrows at the age of 15,)
(لقد شدت حاجبي فقط في سن 15)
(willing to be with you forever.)
(على استعداد أن أكون معك إلى الأبد)
(When I was 16,)
(عندما كان عمره 16 عاما،)
(you left home on a long journey to Yanyudui in Qutang Gorge.)
(غادرت المنزل في رحلة طويلة إلى يانيودوي في وادي تشيوتانغ)
=Romance of a Twin Flower=
= الرومانسية لتوأم الزهرة  =
=Episode 1=
= الحلقة 1 =
(Ning's Mansion)
(قصر نينغ)
(Madam, you woke up.)
(سيدتي، استيقظت)
Great.
عظيم
Yes, take the medicine.
نعم، تناولي الدواء
Miss, who are you?
الآنسة، من أنت؟
Muxu.
موشيو
Muxu?
موشيو؟
I am your personal maid,
أنا خادمتك
(Muxu) Muxu, Your Ladyship.
(موشيو) موشيو، سيدتي
Your Ladyship?
سيدة؟
Yes.
نعم
You are the First Lady
أنت السيدة الأولى
of Marquis Moyu's Mansion.
من قصر ماركيز مويوي
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Don't you like
ألا تحبين
my name?
اسمي؟
Your Ladyship, don't get angry.
سيدتي، لا تغضبي
If you don't like it,
إذا لم يعجبك ذلك
just change my name.
غيّري اسمي فحسب
Celery, Leek, and the like.
الكرفس والكراث وما شابه
Everything will do.
كل شيء ممكن
Don't get angry.
لا تغضبي
Wait, Miss.
انتظري يا آنسة
Don't get angry, Your Ladyship.
لا تغضبي يا سيدتي
- Don't do this. Get up. - Don't get angry.
- لا تفعلي ذلك، قومي - لا تغضبي
Get up. Come on.
قومي، هيا
Well, the Marquis's Mansion
في الواقع، قصر ماركيز
and the First Lady you said
والسيدة الأولى التي قلتها
have nothing to do with me.
لا شيء يخصني
Did you make a mistake?
هل ارتكبت خطأ؟
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
You seem to be different.
يبدو أنك مختلفة
Could it be that you broke your brain
هل يمكن أن تكون أنك كسرت دماغك
when you fell off the cliff?
عندما سقطت من الهاوية؟
Fell off the cliff?
سقطت من الهاوية؟
Who fell off the cliff?
من سقط من الهاوية؟
So crazy.
مجنونة جدا
Miss.
الآنسة
You seem to be occupied.
يبدو أنك مشغولة
I am also busy.
أنا مشغولة أيضا
I have to go.
يجب أن أذهب
You can't get out.
لا يمكنك الخروج
There are so many people guarding outside.
هناك الكثير من الناس يحرسون في الخارج
Why?
لماذا؟
That's because you did...
هذا لأنك فعلت...
You did something wrong.
فعلت شيئًا خاطئًا
That's why you are locked up.
لهذا السبب أنت محبوسة
Marquis has ordered
أمر ماركيز
no one to come or go.
ألا يأتي أحد أو يذهب
I'll just leave for a while.
سأغادر لفترة من الوقت فحسب
Okay.
حسنًا
I'm not leaving.
لن أغادر
Be nice.
كن لطيفًا
I'm not going out.
لن أخرج
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
Look.
انظري
We need to think long term
نحن بحاجة إلى التفكير في الأجل الطويل
about this matter.
بهذه المسألة
I fell off a cliff.
سقطت من الهاوية
Then here I am.
ثم أنا هنا
Yes.
نعم
Then why did I fall off the cliff?
إذن لماذا سقطت من الهاوية؟
What happened
ماذا حدث
before this?
قبل هذا؟
I dare not say.
لا أجرؤ على قول
Why not?
ما السبب؟
You asked me to say it.
طلبت مني أن أقول ذلك
Say it.
قوليها
It all started
بدأ كل شيء
with a chicken.
بديك
A chicken?
ديك؟
(You came here on horseback,)
(جئت إلى هنا على ظهر الخيول،)
(while I was playing with green plum blossoms.)
(بينما كنت ألعب أزهار البرقوق الخضراء)
(Ning's Mansion, Capital) (When I married you at 14 years old,)
(قصر نينغ، العاصمة) (عندما تزوجتك في سن 14 عاما،)
(I was too shy to smile.)
(كنت غاضبة من أن أبتسم)
Get out of the way.
ابتعدوا عن طريقي
(Banxia) Mr. Liu. Mr. Liu.
(بانشيا) السيد ليو
Why are you back so late?
لماذا عدت متأخرا جدا؟
Her Ladyship is waiting anxiously.
السيدة تنتظر بقلق
Okay.
حسنًا
Take it in now.
خذيه الآن
Excuse me. Excuse me.
المعذرة
I don't know
لا أعرف
what Her Ladyship is up to.
ما الذي تفعله السيدة
What did I want a chicken for?
ماذا أريد ديك؟
Your name is Nie Sangyu,
اسمك نيه سانغ يوي
the eldest daughter of
الابنة الأكبر
General Zhenyuan Nie Xiangyuan.
من الجنرال نيه شيانغ يوان
You fell in love with Marquis Moyu Ning Yuxuan at first sight
وقعت في حب ماركيز مويوي نينغ يوي شيوان من النظرة الأولى
and insisted on marrying him.
وأصرت على الزواج منه
And
وأيضا
you have a sobriquet.
لديك لقب
No.1 She-devil of the Capital.
"أشرس امرأة في العاصمة"
She-devil?
أشرس امرأة؟
Coming.
أنا قادمة
Take it out and show me.
خذيه وأريني
Yes, Your Ladyship.
نعم، سيدتي
Come out.
اخرج
Come...
هيا
You!
أنت!
How dare you!
كيف تجرئين!
If you hurt the chicken,
إذا أصبت الديك
you can't pay for your life.
لا يمكنك دفع تكاليف حياتك
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي
Your Ladyship, please show me mercy.
سيدتي، أرجوك أظهري لي الرحمة
Okay.
حسنًا
Someone.
شخص ما
Reward Banxia
أعطى صورة زهر البرقوق الخاص بي
with my plum blossom picture
كمكافأة لبانشيا
as a flower seal.
لختم زهرة
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Your Ladyship, please spare me!
سيدتي، أرجوك أنقذيني!
Your Ladyship!
سيدتي!
(Your Ladyship!)
(سيدتي!)
(Your Ladyship, please spare me!)
(سيدتي، أرجوك أنقذيني!)
(Marquis, Miss Xue!)
(ماركيز، الآنسة شيويه!)
(Save me!)
(أنقذيني!)
(Your Ladyship, please spare me!)
(سيدتي، أرجوك أنقذني!)
(Marquis, Miss Xue!)
(ماركيز، الآنسة شيويه!)
Where is the Marquis?
أين ماركيز؟
(Save me!)
(أنقذني!)
Is the bird's nest
هل عش الطيور
in the kitchen still warm?
في المطبخ لا يزال دافئ؟
(Miss Xue!)
(الآنسة شيويه!)
I'm asking you.
أنا أسألك
Your Ladyship, no worries.
سيدتي، لا قلقي
Marquis has gone to the Politics Hall,
ذهب ماركيز إلى قاعة السياسة
and may not be back until later.
ولا يمكنه العودة حتى وقت لاحق
You can have a meal first.
يمكنك تناول وجبة أولا
No.
لا
(Save me!)
(أنقذني!)
I'm going to wait for him to come back.
سأنتظره للعودة
So horrible.
هذا فظيع جدًا
No, let's not talk about this.
لا، دعينا لا نتحدث عن هذا
Something else.
شيء آخر
Tell me about my husband.
أخبريني عن زوجي
What kind of person is he?
أي نوع من الأشخاص هو؟
Marquis devotes himself to government affairs
ماركيز يكرس نفسه للشؤون الحكومية
and spends most of his time in the Politics Hall.
ويقضي معظم وقته في قاعة السياسة
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك
he achieves success when young,
يحقق النجاح عندما يكون صغيرا
and is the Left Consul of the present dynasty.
وهو القنصل المساعد في السلالة الحالية
He's also No. 1 Handsome Man of the Capital.
إنه الرجل الأكثر وسامة في العاصمة
(Central Secretariat)
(الأمانة المركزية)
(Politics Hall)
(قاعة السياسات)
Sir.
سيدي
This is the relevant document
هذه هي الوثيقة ذات الصلة
compiled on the case of
التي تم جمعها بشأن قضية
(From Minister of Water, Lu Wenbin) flood prevention and control in the southeast.
(من وزير المياه، لو ونبين) منع الفيضانات ومكافحتها في الجنوب الشرقي
Please take a look.
يرجى إلقاء نظرة
Flood prevention and control?
منع الفيضانات ومكافحتها؟
It is the flood season,
إنه موسم الفيضانات
and floods broke out frequently.
وحدثت الفيضانات بشكل متكرر
(From Minister of Water, Lu Wenbin) The stricken people are suffering.
(من وزير المياه، لو ونبين) الناس يعانون
However, disaster relief matters
ومع ذلك، فإن مسائل الإغاثة في حالات الكوارث
involve a wide range of issues, and implementation is slow.
تنطوي على طائفة واسعة من القضايا والتنفيذ بطيء
So I think
لذلك أعتقد
it's better to plan early.
من الأفضل التخطيط مبكرا
Taking precautions
اتخاذ الاحتياطات
is indeed a must.
هو بالفعل أمر لا بد منه
Mr. Ning, you are really thoughtful.
السيد نينغ، أنت ذكي جدًا
I'm flattered.
شكرا للمدح
By the way, sir.
بالمناسبة يا سيدي
I have a presumptuous request.
لدي طلب
Go ahead.
تفضل
I have to take three days off
يجب أن آخذ إجازة ثلاثة أيام
due to my marriage.
بسبب زواجي
By then, you and
إذن أنت
my colleagues
وزملائي
are invited to attend.
المدعوون للحضور
Approved.
تمت الموافقة عليها
Just go.
اذهب
Thank you, sir.
شكرًا سيدي
(Self-discipline for Justice)
(الانضباط الذاتي من أجل العدالة)
Mr. Liu.
السيد ليو
The Ministry of Justice urgently reported that
وزارة العدل أفادت على وجه الاستعجال أنه
a group of bandits appeared in the south of the city.
ظهر مجموعة من قطاع الطرق في جنوب مدينة
Bandits?
قطاع الطرق؟
Yes.
نعم
How come?
لماذا؟
So he is a good officer.
إذن إنه ضابط جيد
You have done so many evil things.
لقد فعلت الكثير من الأشياء الشريرة
Do you really think you can escape the punishment of the law?
هل تظن حقا أنك تستطيع الهروب من عقوبة القانون؟
There are so many choices
هناك الكثير من الخيارات
in the world,
في العالم
but you became a bandit who brings troubles to people.
لكنك أصبحت قطاع الطرق الذي يجلب المشاكل إلى الناس
Now that you are a bandit,
بما أن أصبحت قطاع الطرق
you should have expected today.
كان يجب أن تتوقع اليوم
It seems that my husband
يبدو أن زوجي
is a decisive bandit-suppressing hero.
هو بطل حاسم لقمع قطاع الطرق
There must be many girls
لا بد من وجود العديد من الفتيات
who like him.
يحبونه
Right.
صحيح
Yesterday was the day
كان أمس
when Marquis married
يوم تزوج ماركيز فيه
his second wife.
من زوجته الثانية
Second wife?
الزوجة الثانية؟
He has me.
لديه أنا
Why did he get married again?
لماذا تزوج مجددًا؟
Marquis took a concubine for the first time
أخذ ماركيز محظية للمرة الأولى
after four years of marriage.
بعد أربع سنوات من الزواج
You must be sad, Your Ladyship.
لا بد أن تكوني حزينة يا سيدتي
Listen.
استمعي
Good-looking men
الرجال الوسيمون
are all philandering.
كلهم لعوبون
Is everything arranged at home?
هل كل شيء مرتب في المنزل؟
Yes.
نعم
(Gui Bai) The guards on patrol have doubled.
(قي باي) تضاعف الحراس في الدورية
Our people will be placed
سيتم وضع أشخاصنا
among the guests.
بين الضيوف
In the process of encircling and suppressing bandits over the years,
في عملية قمع قطاع الطرق على مر السنين
there are many escaped criminals.
هناك العديد من المجرمين الفارين
Today is my wedding day.
اليوم هو يوم زفافي
I hope they don't miss
آمل ألا يفوتوا
the chance for revenge.
فرصة الانتقام
(Your Lordship.)
(سيدتي)
(Marquis doesn't allow anyone to enter.)
(ماركيز لا يسمح لأحد بالدخول)
Your Ladyship, you can't get in.
سيدتي، لا يمكنك الدخول
Your Ladyship. Your Ladyship.
سيدتي، سيدتي
You can't get in.
لا يمكنك الدخول
Your Ladyship, you can't get in.
سيدتي، لا يمكنك الدخول
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Marquis said you can't get in.
ماركيز قال إنك لا يمكنك الدخول
Don't get in.
لا تدخلي
Are you really going to marry her?
هل ستتزوجها حقا؟
Gui Bai.
قي باي
Is this your deployment?
هل هذا توزيعك؟
Anyone can break in.
يمكن لأي شخص أن يدخل
I disagree.
أنا لا أتفق
I don't allow you to marry her.
أنا لا أسمح لك بالزواج منها
Go back to your room.
عودي إلى غرفتك
I am the hostess of this mansion.
أنا مضيفة هذا القصر
I don't allow you to marry her.
لا أسمح لك بالزواج منها
Someone.
تعال شخص ما
Take First Lady back to the room.
خذ السيدة الأولى إلى الغرفة
She'll be grounded today.
سيتم حصرها اليوم
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي
Ning Yuxuan!
نينغ يوي شيوان!
No! Ning Yuxuan!
لا! نينغ يوي شيوان!
Your Ladyship, let's go.
سيدتي، دعينا نذهب
Ning Yuxuan!
نينغ يوي شيوان!
You can't marry her.
لا يمكنك الزواج منها
Don't touch me!
لا تلمساني!
Remember.
تذكر
I am the hostess of the mansion.
أنا مضيفة القصر
It seems that the relationship
يبدو أن العلاقة بيننا
between us isn't good at all,
ليست جيدة على الإطلاق
is it?
أليس كذلك؟
Now that he went to suppress the bandits,
بما أن ذهب لقمع قطاع الطرق
who would pick up the bride?
من سيأخذ العروس؟
(Wen's Mansion) The bride is out.
(قصر ون) تخرج العروس
Where is Marquis?
أين ماركيز؟
Why hasn't he arrived yet?
لماذا لم يصل بعد؟
Marquis...
ماركيز
Marquis has something important to do
ماركيز لديه شيء مهم لفعله
and can't make it here.
ولا يمكن أن يأتي
At the order
أنا تحت
of the First Lady,
أمر السيدة الأولى
I came to pick up the Second Lady.
أتيت لآخذ من السيدة الثانية
You alone?
أنت بمفردك؟
Not me.
ليس أنا
That's it.
بل هو
How can you get a cock to pick up the bride?
كيف يمكن ديك لأخذ العروس؟
Why would I force her
لماذا أجبرها
to marry a cock?
على الزواج من ديك؟
Because you were like that
لأنك كنت هكذا
back then.
في ذلك الوقت
Back then...
في ذلك الوقت...
I was like that?
كنت هكذا؟
I held a wedding ceremony with a chicken?
عقدت حفل زفاف مع ديك؟
What about the wedding after that?
ماذا عن الزفاف بعد ذلك؟
Here comes the bride.
ها قد أتت العروس
It's easy to mix in today.
من السهل الدخول في اليوم
Ning's Mansion's patrol
دورية قصر نينغ
shouldn't be so loose.
لا يجب أن تكون فضالة جدًا
It's Lackey Ning's wedding day.
إنه يوم زواج نينغ
He must have been negligent.
لا بد أنه كان مهملا
Ask our people to be careful.
اطلب من أشخاصنا أن يكونوا حذرين
Okay.
حسنا
Just in case.
في حالة فقط
Here comes Mr. Ning.
هنا يأتي السيد نينغ
(Wen Wan)
(ون وان)
Your Lordship, here you are.
سيدي، ها أنت ذا
Let's get started.
دعينا نبدأ
Here.
إليك
Now is the auspicious time.
الآن هو الوقت الميمونة
Groom and bride.
العروس والعروس
The first kowtow is for heaven and earth.
الركوع الأول هو للسماء والأرض
Ning Yuxuan!
نينغ يوي شيوان!
Wait, Your Ladyship.
انتظري يا سيدتي
Here comes the First Lady.
ها قد أتت السيدة الأولى
With me here,
معك أنا هنا
you can never marry her.
لا يمكنك الزواج منها أبدًا
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
Watch your behavior.
انتبهي لسلوكك
I don't care.
لا يهمني
Since we can't be a couple
بما أننا لا يمكن أن نكون زوجين
in this life,
في هذه الحياة
no one else can think about it.
لا يمكن لأحد أن يفكر في ذلك
Mr. Liu.
السيد ليو
Go ahead.
تفضل
Groom and bride.
العريس والعروس
The first kowtow is for heaven and earth.
الركوع الأول هو للسماء والأرض
Okay.
حسنًا
You forced me to do so.
أجبرتني على القيام بذلك
Wen Wan!
ون وان!
Call the doctor.
اتصل بالطبيب
Call the doctor!
اتصلوا بالطبيب
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
It's not me!
ليس أنا
Lackey Ning.
نينغ
Go to hell!
اذهب إلى الجحيم!
It's not me!
ليس أنا
Here you are!
ها أنت ذا!
Wen Wan!
ون وان!
- Your Lordship, watch out! - Gui Bai!
- سيدي، انتبه! - قوي باي!
Let's go!
لنذهب
Don't let go any of them.
لا تتركوا أيا منهم
Yes!
نعم
Did Miss Wen
هل ماتت السيدة ون
just die?
هكذا؟
No. No.
لا
Miss Wen wasn't stabbed in the vital part.
لم تطعن السيدة ون في الجزء الحيوي
She is recuperating in the mansion.
إنها تتعافى في القصر
That's good.
هذا جيد
I think that
أعتقد
you must have hurt your brain
لا بد أنك جرحت دماغك
when you fell off the cliff.
عندما سقطت من الهاوية
I'll get you the medicine.
سأحضر لك الدواء
Maybe the memory will come back
ربما ستعود الذاكرة
after you take it.
بعد أن تأخذيه
Hold on.
انتظري
No worries about taking medicine.
لا قلقي بشأن تناول الدواء
My top priority now is
أولويتي القصوى الآن هي
trying to escape.
محاولة الهروب
(Your Ladyship.)
(سيدتي)
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Marquis asked you to the study.
ماركيز طلب منك بالذهاب إلى مكتب الدراسة
Marquis?
ماركيز؟
I'm not going.
لن أذهب
Muxu.
موشيو
You just said that
أنت قلت للتو
he's No. 1 Handsome Man
إنه الرجل الأكثر وسامة
of the Capital, right?
في العاصمة، أليس كذلك؟
Have you caught all the bandits
هل قبضت على جميع قطاع الطرق
who assassinated at the wedding?
الذين اغتالوا في الزفاف؟
Your Lordship.
سيدي
Three of them escaped.
فر ثلاثة منهم
Check out those caught ones.
تحقق من الذين نمسك بهم
If I'm right,
إذا كنت على حق
it must have something to do with the Tea Gang.
يجب أن يكون لديهم علاقة بعصابة الشاي
Yes.
نعم
Marquis.
ماركيز
Here comes the First Lady.
ها قد أتت السيدة الأولى
Your Lordship.
سيدي
Leave us alone.
غادروا أنتم
Yes.
نعم
Honey.
عزيزي
(A gentleman should also constantly pursue progress just like nature.)
(ينبغي لرجل نبيل أن يكون دائما متابع التقدم مثل الطبيعة تماما)
♪The singing and dancing in the palace garden is over♪
♪ينتهي الغناء والرقص في القصر♪
♪The bright moon shines on the sad wanderers♪
♪ القمر الساطع يشع على المتشائمين حزينين ♪
♪Admiring the flowers in a lonely boat, and the flowers remain the same♪
♪التمتع بالزهور في قارب والزهور تظل كما هي♪
♪After a rain, the chill is gone♪
♪ بعد المطر، يختفي البرد ♪
(His gentle appearance)
(مظهره الوسيم)
(is not as sinister)
(ليس شريرا)
(as Muxu described.)
(كما وصفت موشيو)
(Maybe my relationship with him)
(ربما علاقتي به)
(is not so bad.)
(ليست سيئة جدًا)
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
Honey.
عزيزي
I heard
سمعت
there was some misunderstanding
كان هناك سوء فهم ما
between us.
بيننا
But I believe that
لكنني أعتقد أنه
it won't affect
لن يؤثر
our relationship, right?
على علاقتنا، صحيح؟
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
Your crime of disturbing
إن جريمتك المتمثلة في إزعاج قصر نينغ
the Ning's Mansion is unforgivable.
لا تُغتفر
Stop.
توقف
I know what you're going to say.
أعرف ما ستقوله
That's why
لهذا السبب
I feel wronged.
أشعر بالظلم
None of these things
لم أفعل هذه الأشياء
was done by me.
من قبلي
Are you acting enough?
هل تتظاهرين بما فيه الكفاية؟
I wasn't acting.
لم أكن أتظاهر
Do you need me
هل تحتاجين إلي
to remind you
لتذكّرك
how you broke into the wedding banquet
كيف اقتحمت مأدبة الزفاف
and assassinated Wen Wan?
لاغتيال ون وان؟
I really
أنا حقا
can't remember these.
لا أستطيع تذكر هذه
You are my husband.
أنت زوجي
You have to do me justice.
عليك أن تحقق لي العدالة
(Don't judge anyone by appearance.)
(لا تحكم على أحد بالمظهر)
(His personality is terrible.)
(شخصيته سيئة)
It's possible that
من الممكن أنه
I lost my mind
فقدت عقلي
after falling off the cliff.
بعد أن سقطت من الهاوية
I'll go back and think about it.
سأعود وأفكّر في الأمر
Stop!
وقفي!
(Statement of Confession) Sign it.
(بيان الاعتراف) وقعي عليه
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Statement of Confession?
بيان الاعتراف؟
The criminal Nie Sangyu
نيه سانغ يوي
did violence and abused servants.
قامت بأعمال عنف لخدم
Her methods are vicious and her crimes are serious.
أساليبها شريرة وجرائمها خطيرة
She voluntarily moves to Reflection Pavilion to repent,
تنتقل طواعية إلى جناح التأمل لتتوب
and promises to
وتعد
spend the rest of her life in the Marquis's Mansion.
أن قضاء بقية حياتها في قصر ماركيز
If she commits the crime again,
إذا ارتكبت الجريمة مرة أخرى
she will be at Ning Yuxuan's disposal.
ستكون تحت تصرف نينغ يوي شيوان
(He looks so handsome.)
(يبدو وسيمًا جدًا)
(But he's so evil-minded.)
(لكنه وحشي جدا)
I can't sign it.
لا أستطيع توقيع ذلك
For the sake of the four years of our marriage,
لمدة أربع سنوات من زواجنا
you only need to sign the statement of confession,
تحتاجين فقط إلى توقيع بيان الاعتراف
move into Reflection Pavilion,
وانتقلي إلى جناح التأمل
and spend the rest of your life there
لقضاء بقية حياتك هناك
from now on.
من الآن فصاعدًا
Why should I admit to
لماذا يجب أن أعترف
something I haven't done?
يشيء لم أفعله؟
Sign the statement of confession.
توقعي على بيان الاعتراف
This is your only chance.
هذه فرصتك الوحيدة
I won't sign it.
لن أوقع عليه
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
Sign it or not?
التوقيع عليه أم لا؟
What are you going to do?
ماذا ستفعلان؟
I have interrogated more than a thousand prisoners.
لقد استجوبت أكثر من ألف سجين
Tricks like faking a faint
الحيل مثل التظاهر بفقدان الوعي
are long outdated.
عفا عليها الزمن
I can't admit it.
لا أستطيع الاعتراف بذلك
I didn't do it.
لم أفعل ذلك
Stop challenging my patience.
كفّي عن تحدي صبري
I will give you
سأعطيك
one last chance.
فرصة أخيرة
Sign the statement of confession,
توقعي بيان الاعتراف
and move into Reflection Pavilion.
وانتقلي إلى جناح التأمل
(Since my acting doesn't work,)
(بما أن تمثيلي لا يعمل،)
(I have no choice but to...)
(لا خيار لي سوى...)
I heard before that
سمعت
you are the Left Consul
أنك القنصل الأيمن
who is famous all over the capital.
الذي هو مشهور في جميع أنحاء العاصمة
Then
إذن
if everyone knows that
إذا كان الجميع يعرف أنه
you have a sinful woman as your legal wife,
لديك امرأة شريرة كزوجة قانونية لك
what should they think of you?
ما رأيهم بك؟
I can't do that.
لا أستطيع فعل ذلك
Everyone in the capital
الجميع في العاصمة
knows your reputation,
يعرف سمعتك
Nie Sangyu.
نيه سانغ يوي
I don't care anymore.
لا يهمني ذلك
Wait...
مهلًا...
I don't care if you're playing the fool
لا يهمني إن كنت تتظاهرين
or you've really lost your memory,
وأم فقدت ذاكرتك حقًا
what's done is done.
لقد حدث ما حدث
You can't deny it.
لا يمكنك إنكار الأمر
A day together as a couple
يوم معا كزوجين
means endless devotion.
يعني تفانيا لا نهاية له
- We've never spent a day together. - For the sake of...
- لم نقض يوما معا أبدا - من أجل...
Could it be that
هل يمكن أن تكون
you are still...
لا تزال...
You are still...
أنت لا تزالين...
Sign the statement of confession.
وقعي بيان الاعتراف
This is the last time I'll say it.
هذه آخر مرة أقولها
(It seems that if I don't sign the statement of confession,)
(يبدو أنني لا أستطيع المغادرة هنا...)
(I can't leave here.)
(إذا لم أوقع عليه)
(Forget it.)
(انسى الأمر)
(Just sign it.)
(مجرد التوقيع عليه)
I will sign it.
سأوقع عليه
Why so angry?
لماذا بهذا الغضب؟
Okay, done.
حسنًا، انتهيت
I will move to the Reflection Pavilion.
سأانتقل إلى جناح التأمل
Nie Sangyu!
نيه سانغ يوي!
I promised to sign it.
وعدت أن أوقع عليه
But I didn't say what to sign.
لكنني لم أقل ماذا أوقع
(Reflection Pavilion)
(جناح التأمل)
After moving into the Reflection Pavilion,
بعد الانتقال إلى جناح التأمل
we are done.
لقد انتهينا
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
What's this?
ما هذا؟
This...
هذا...
What if...
ماذا لو
can't leave here anymore?
لا يمكننا المغادرة هنا بعد الآن؟
Marquis really asked us
طلب منا ماركيز
to stay here?
بالبقاء هنا حقا؟
Now that Marquis asked us to stay here,
بما أن ماركيز طلب منا أن نبقى هنا الآن
let's live a good life here
دعينا نعيش حياة جيدة هنا
as he expected.
كما توقع
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Didn't you use to hate
ألم تكرهين
these dirty and shabby places the most?
هذه الأماكن القذرة والمظلمة الأكثر؟
You had to bypass these places
كان عليك تجاوز هذه الأماكن
when you got out in a sedan chair.
عندما خرجت بكرسي سيدان
Since
بما أننا
we are already here,
هنا بالفعل
take things as they come.
خذي الأشياء بينما تأتي
Muxu.
موشيو
Listen.
استمعي
Put it
ضعيه
here.
هنا
Here.
هكذا
Come back
عودي
in six hours,
بعد ست ساعات
okay?
اتفقنا؟
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Stop.
توقفي
The ground is slippery with water.
الأرض انزلقت مع الماء
I'll be done right away.
سأنهي على الفور
No worries.
لا قلقي
Are you still the same person?
هل ما زلت نفس الشخص؟
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
You have never done
لم تفعلي أبدا
this kind of manual labor before.
هذا النوع من العمل اليدوي من قبل
Why are you doing better than me?
لماذا تفعلي أفضل مني؟
If I don't hurry up,
إذا لم أسرع
where shall we live tonight?
أين سنعيش الليلة؟
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Let me serve you a glass of water.
دعيني أقدم لك كأس ماء
No need.
لا حاجة
Put it there.
ضعيه هناك
I am not thirsty.
أنا لست عطشانة
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Don't be like this.
لا توكني هكذا
I'm afraid.
أنا خائفة ذلك
You weren't like this before.
لم توكني هكذا من قبل
What's wrong, Muxu?
ما الخطب يا مو شيوي؟
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
I may not have been like this before.
ربما لم أكن هكذا من قبل
But
ولكن
from today on,
من اليوم فصاعدا
I am
أنا أكون أنا
who I am now.
من أكون الآن
It will never change.
لن أغير أبدًا
But...
لكن
I know
أعرف أنني فعلت الكثير من الأشياء
I've done a lot of things in the past
في الماضي
that even made myself
لدرجة أنني
feel unbelievable.
لا أصدقها حتى
But I promise you that
لكنني أعدك بأنني
I will never
لن أدعك
let you live in fear
تعيشين في خوف
from now on.
من الآن فصاعدًا
Could you trust me?
هل يمكنك الوثوق بي؟
I trust you.
أنا أثق بك
Your Ladyship, let's have dinner.
سيدتي، دعينا نتناول العشاء
The dinner is here?
العشاء هنا؟
Take it out.
أحضره
Come on.
هيا
Anything delicious?
أي شيء لذيذ؟
Here.
هنا
One more.
واحدة أخرى
More?
المزيد؟
Here.
تفضلي
Please eat.
كلي من فضلك
That's all?
كل هذا؟
That's all.
هذا كل ما في الأمر
No meat?
لا لحم؟
Meat?
اللحم؟
You have been a vegetarian for many years
لقد كنت تأكلين نباتات لسنوات عديدة
to pray for Marquis.
للصلاة من أجل ماركيز
I have also been vegetarian
لقد كنت أيضا آكل النباتات
with you for a long time.
معك لفترة طويلة
I have been vegetarian for him for many years?
لقد كنت آكل النباتات من أجله لسنوات عديدة
I...
أنا...
I love him that much?
أنا أحبه إلى هذه الدرجة؟
Regardless of whether you are a vegetarian or not,
بغض النظر عما إذا كنت تأكلين النباتات أم لا
Marquis specially ordered that
ماركيز قد طلب خصيصا
those who came to Reflection Pavilion
أولئك الذين جاءوا إلى جناح التأمل
can only have this kind of meal.
يمكن فقط تناول هذا النوع من الوجبة
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Don't be upset.
لا تنزعجي
Right now,
الآن
you'd better eat more
من الأفضل أن تأكلي أكثر
and conserve your strength.
للحفاظ على قوتك
Only in this way
فقط بهذه الطريقة
can we have a chance
يمكننا أن تتاح لنا الفرصة
to turn over.
لتسليم نفسك
You are right.
أنت على حق
Beggars
متسولون
can't be choosers.
لا يمكن أن يكونوا خانقين
To conserve strength.
للحفاظ على القوة
Eat!
هيا!
I'll serve you dishes.
سأقدم لك الأطباق
Okay.
حسنًا
Here, eat more.
هيا، كلي المزيد
It's really not like her.
إنها لا تشبها حقا
When you rescued her
عندما أنقذتها
back then,
في ذلك الوقت
were you sure it was her?
هل كنت متأكدا من أنها هي؟
Absolutely sure.
بالتأكيد
I can never
لا أستطيع أبدا بخطأ
mistake Her Ladyship.
في شكل السيدة
You mean
أنت تقصد
Lady never scolded you before.
لم توبخك السيدة من قبل
She had great respect for you before.
كانت تحترمك كثيرًا من قبل
But now she's so bold.
لكنها الآن جريئة جدًا
Look at the font.
انظر إلى الخط
Nie Sangyu has studied lower script since she was a child,
مارست في الخط منذ أنها كانت طفلة
and her characters are delicate.
وخطها دقيقة
But these profound and powerful words
لكن هذه الكلمات العميقة والقوية
cannot be written
لا يمكن كتابتها
without more than ten years of practice.
دون أكثر من عشر سنوات من الممارسة
What's
ما لدى
Nie Sangyu up to?
يه سانغ يوي؟
(There should be something inside.)
(يجب أن يكون هناك شيء في الداخل)
What?
ماذا؟
In the huge Ning's Mansion,
في قصر نينغ الضخم
there is not even food in the pot.
لا يوجد حتى الطعام في الوعاء
So many goodies.
الكثير من الأطعمة
I'm so amazing.
أنا مذهلة
It's not burnt.
هذا لم يحترق
I can't call for help.
لا يمكنني طلب المساعدة
Why is the fire growing stronger?
لماذا يزداد الحريق قوة؟
There's no need to do this for a meal.
لا داعي لفعل هذا من أجل وجبة طعام
I'd better run.
من الأفضل أن أركض
Who locked the door?
من أوصد الباب؟
Open the door! Help!
افتح الباب! النجدة!
Fire!
النار!
Fire! Put out the fire!
اخمد النار!
Come on.
هيا
Go get more water.
اذهب واحصل على المزيد من الماء
I'll go get some water.
سأذهب لأحضر بعض الماء
Come on! Water!
هيا! ماء!
Over there!
هناك!
If I had known earlier...
لو كنت أعرف هذا...
If I had known earlier,
لو كنت أعرف هذا من قبل
I might as well have died falling off a cliff yesterday.
أفضل أن أموت من السقوط أمس
I was about to die in a fire
كنت على وشك أن أموت في حريق
just one day after coming back to life.
بعد العودة إلى الحياة بيوم واحد فقط
Come on. Over there.
هيا، هناك
Okay, coming.
حسنًا، أنا قادمة
Here, come on.
هيا
Your Lordship.
سيدتي
The fire is fierce here.
الحريق محتدم هنا
Go back first and I'll take care of it.
عد أولا، وسأهتم بالأمر
Your Lordship.
جلالتك
The kitchen was on fire
كان المطبخ في حريق
when we got here.
عندما وصلنا إلى هنا
If it goes on,
إذا استمر
the whole mansion will be burnt down.
سيتم احراق القصر بأكمله
Ask someone to tear it down.
اطلب من أحدهم أن يدمره
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي
Tear it down.
دمر المنزل
Okay.
حسنا
Save me!
أنقذني!
Get ready to tear it down.
استعدي لهدم المكان
Anyone there?
أي شخص هناك؟
Save me!
النجدة!
Someone's inside.
شخص ما في الداخل
Hurry up!
أسرعي!
Someone's there.
شخص ما هناك
Your Lordship, what are you going to do?
سيدتي، ماذا ستفعل؟
You have always been most afraid of fire.
هل كنت دائما أكثر خوفا من النار
Step aside.
ابتعد
No.
لا
Your Lordship!
سيدي!
Gui Bai!
قوي باي!
Your Ladyship.
سيدتي
Here.
هيا
Take care.
اعتني بنفسك
Your Lordship, are you okay?
سيدي، هل أنت بخير؟
So you were outside?
لذلك كنت في الخارج؟
I just yelled for a long time.
صرخت لمدة طويلة
I thought there was no...
ظننت أنه لا يوجد
Nie Sangyu!
نيه سانغ يوي!
You performed an assassination at the wedding last time.
قمت باغتيال في حفل الزفاف المرة الماضية
And you set fire this time.
وأشعلت النار هذه المرة
Do you want everyone in the mansion
هل تريدين أن يموت الجميع في القصر
to die with you?
معك؟
I was locked inside.
كنت مُحتجزة في الداخل
I didn't set the fire.
لم أشعل النار
Then why are you here
إذن لماذا أنت هنا
dressed like this?
وترتدين مثل هذه الملابس؟
Your Lordship.
سيدي
What's wrong with you?
ما خطبك؟
Piss off!
ابتعدي!
You are injured.
أنت مصاب
Take me away.
خذني بعيدا
Yes.
نعم
Where are you hurt?
أين تأذيت؟
More water.
المزيد من المياه
Your Lordship.
سيدي
What's wrong with you?
ما خطبك؟
Piss off!
ابتعدي!
Your Ladyship, your soothing tea.
سيدتي، الشاي الخاص بك
Muxu.
موشيو
Do you know
هل تعرفين
why Ning Yuxuan
لماذا نينغ يوي شيوان
suddenly became like that?
أصبح هكذا فجأة؟
I have no idea.
لا أعلم
But
لكن
I think
أعتقد
Marquis cares about you very much.
أن ماركيز يهتم بك كثيرا
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك
he wouldn't have rushed into the fire
ما كان ليركض إلى النار
to save you.
لإنقاذك
It makes sense.
هذا منطقي
He looks fierce.
يبدو شرسا
But he still has a conscience.
لكنه لا يزال لديه ضمير
You were frightened today.
كنت خائفة اليوم
Go to bed earlier.
اذهبي للنوم باكرا
I'm going to lock the door now.
سأغلق الباب الآن
Wait.
انتظري
What's wrong, Your Ladyship?
ما الخطب يا سيدتي؟
The kitchen door
باب المطبخ
was locked by someone.
كان مسجونا من قبل شخص ما
Someone wanted to kill me.
أراد شخص ما قتلي
Your Lordship.
سيدي
Your symptoms flared up again.
اشتعلت أعراضك مرة أخرى
How about I go get a doctor?
ما رأيك أن أذهب لأحضر طبيبا؟
No need.
لا حاجة
I know what to do.
أعرف ماذا أفعل
Your Lordship.
سيدي
You are only curbing the disease
أنت فقط تحد من المرض
by dousing yourself in ice water like this.
عن طريق مضاعفة نفسك في مياه الثلج هكذا
The disease cannot be eradicated.
لا يمكن القضاء على المرض
Habit cures habit.
العادة يشفي من العادة
Get out.
اخرج
Out!
اخرج!
Yes, sir.
نعم، سيدي
Save me!
أنقذني!
Dad!
أبي!
(It's been so many years.)
(لقد مر الكثير من السنوات)
(Why am I still so afraid of fire?)
(لماذا ما زلت خائفا جدا من النار؟)
(When exactly)
(متى بالضبط)
(can I overcome the demon inside?)
(يمكنني التغلب على الشيطان في القلب؟)
Dad!
أبي!
Ning Yuxuan.
نينغ يوي تشيوان
Ning Yuxuan, it's me.
نينغ يوي شيوان، هذا أنا
Listen.
استمع
I think what happened in the kitchen...
أظن أن ما حدث في المطبخ
Put on your clothes.
ارتد ملابسك
I didn't mean to
لم أقصد
watch you take a bath.
أن أراك تستحم
I'm not interested
أنا لست مهتمة
even if you're naked.
حتى لو كنت عاريا
I'll count to three.
سأعد إلى ثلاثة
Put on your clothes.
ارتد ملابسك
One.
واحد
Two.
اثنان
I'm turning around.
سأدير رأسي
But you...
لكنك...
♪Summer stars, autumn night♪
♪ نجوم الصيف، ليلة الخريف ♪
♪Who is wandering under the moon in my heart♪
♪ من يتجول في قلبي تحت القمر ♪
♪The deepest story with the shallowest goodbye♪
♪ أعمق قصة مع أسطح الوداع  ♪
♪After passing by, I can only meet you in my dream♪
♪ بعد المرور من هنا لا يمكنني إلا أن ألتقي بك في حلمي ♪
♪The wind can't breeze the long street of time♪
♪ لا يمكن للريح أن تهب على شارع طويل من الزمن ♪
♪The burning yearning will never cool♪
♪ الشوق المحترق لن يكون باردا أبدا ♪
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ قلبتان يلتقيان مرة أخرى وينذران بالحب ♪
♪How can I describe it when we look into each other's eyes♪
♪ كيف يمكنني وصفها عندما ننظر في عيون بعضنا البعض ♪
♪Take a life time to write the story♪
♪ خذ وقت حياة لكتابة القصة ♪
♪Together with you♪
♪ معك ♪
♪Company you♪
♪ الارتباط معك ♪
♪Just for your glance and smile♪
♪ فقط من أجل نظرك وابتسامك ♪
♪The first promise means the forever love♪
♪ الوعد الأول يعني الحب إلى الأبد ♪
♪Fireworks all over the sky light up your night♪
♪ الألعاب النارية تضيء ليلتك ♪
♪Take a life time♪
♪ أخذ وقت الحياة ♪
♪To write the story with you gradually♪
♪ لكتابة القصة معك تدريجيا ♪
♪Just like this♪
♪ هكذا ♪
♪Our love goes on and on♪
♪ حبنا يستمر إلا مطاف النهاية ♪
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ اليوم الذي التقينا فيه لأول مرة السنة عندما نتقدم في السن ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ قلبي وحبي لن يختفي أبدًا ♪